《哥谭》前情提要
Previously on Gotham...
我衷心祝愿
My best wishes to...
艾森局长  工作顺利
Commissioner Essen.
欢迎回来  吉姆
Welcome back, Jim.
我不知道你是怎么办到的
I don't know how you pulled this off,
但我很高兴你办到了
but I'm glad you did.
有时候  正确的路
Sometimes, the right way
不也是肮脏的路吗
is also the ugly way.
阿卡姆精神病院出事了
There's been an incident. At Arkham Asylum.
六名病人越狱了
Six inmates have escaped.
芭芭拉·基恩也在其中
Barbara Kean was one of them.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
世人视你们为精神病罪犯
The world sees criminal lunatics.
我看到的却是天才
I see brilliance.
哥谭会在你们面前颤抖
Gotham would tremble before you.
求求你  我的儿子
"I beg of you, my son,
一定要选择幸福
please choose happiness.
除非你找到了自己的使命
"Unless you feel a calling.
真正的使命"
A true calling."
市长先生
Mr. Mayor,
你想知道我的真面目吗
you want to know what I really am?
当然了  先生
Yes, sir.
我该告诉你吗
Shall I tell you?
说吧  请说
Please, please.
我心底里
At heart...
是个勤于研究人性的学生
I'm an ardent student of human nature.
我们都是有趣的驳论
Fascinating paradox, we are.
机智  却又愚蠢
So wise, and yet so foolish.
勇敢  却又胆怯
So brave, and yet so fearful.
比方说这个玻璃罐
For instance, this is a glass jar.
里面有只长毛蜘蛛
Inside of it is a hairy spider.
可能是毒狼蛛  我也说不准
A tarantula, I guess, but I'm no expert.
一分钟后  我就会打开你箱子上的盖子
In a minute, I'm gonna open that little hatch in the front of your box,
把蜘蛛放进去
I'm gonna drop the spider inside,
然后关上盖子
and I'm gonna close it.
这是A选项
That's choice A.
B选项就是我打开盖子
Choice B, I open the hatch,
你给你可爱的秘书玛姬打电话
you speak to your lovely secretary Maggie on the telephone,
告诉她你跟个女人私奔了
you tell her you've run away with some woman,
稍后就把详细指示发给她
you'll be sending written instructions shortly.
那么选哪个  A还是B
So which is it, choice A or choice B?
B  拜托  我选B
Choice B, please. Please, choice B.
电话
The telephone.
当然
Of course.
人性使然
It's human nature.
看到了吗
See?
没有蜘蛛
There is no spider.
但你要没按我说的做  下场会比那更惨
But if you don't do what I ask, you'll wish there was one.
你为什么这么对我
Why are you doing this to me?
别急
Don't fret so.
你是大局的一部分
You're part of a great endeavor.
伟大的净化
A great cleansing.
怪物要来了  市长先生
Monsters are coming, Mr. Mayor.
怪物
Monsters.
他们将用烈火与鲜血
Who will cleanse this city
净化这座城市
in blood and fire.
詹姆斯市长去哪了  神秘情妇是何人
这是什么
What the hell is this?
"詹姆斯市长去哪了
"Where is Mayor James?
神秘情妇是何人"
Who is his mystery lover?"
没人在乎市长跟谁搞上了
No one cares who the mayor is banging!
你们能做得更好的
You can do better than this, people.
出去给我挖点头条新闻出来  该死
Now go out and get me some headlines, damn it!
好了  好了
Yeah. All right, all right.
天呐
Oh, my God.
完美
Perfect.
下一个
Next.
X先生
Mr. X.
本字幕由ZiMuZu原创翻译  最新下载请登录www.ZiMuZu.tv
翻译 艾瑞卡   小酸奶!   Silence   DustD   Reginamoon
翻译 charcie   木浅   爵士年代蓬蓬裙   夜影章鱼X   草草
稍微往右边挪一点
Uh, a little to the right.
好  就是那个位置
Okay, that's the spot.
时间轴 风吹来的那片云
时间轴 永远的永远   后期 宝宝   校对 草草   总监 草草
完美
Perfect.
那多出来的这个...怎么办
What shall we do with the... spare?
我知道了
I know.
亚伦
Aaron.
有劳了
Would you kindly?
疯子帮
"疯子帮"
"Maniax!"
这才叫头条
Now that's a headline.
哥谭
第二季  第二集
情况大家都知道
You all know what we're facing here.
48小时前  六名精神病罪犯
48 hours ago, six criminally insane inmates
被劫狱逃离了阿卡姆疯人院
were busted out of Arkham Asylum.
昨天  其中四人闯入了耶伦船坞
Yesterday, four of those inmates broke into Yellen Shipyard,
绑架了七名工人
kidnapped seven workers,
然后把他们从《哥谭公报》大楼顶上扔了下来
then dropped them off the roof of the Gotham Gazette.
到现在为止  我们还不知道
As of now, we still have no leads
这场劫囚是谁主使的
on the person or persons behind the breakout.
吉姆·戈登负责行动  吉姆
Jim Gordon's lead. Jim.
以下是我们的目标
These are our targets.
杰罗姆·瓦勒斯卡  18岁
Jerome Valeska, 18 years old.
弑母
Matricide.
阿诺德·道布金斯
Arnold Dobkins,
精神分裂
schizophrenic.
投毒者
Poisoner,
强奸犯
rapist.
亚伦·赫尔辛格
Aaron Helzinger.
赤手空拳杀死了全家人
Killed his entire family with his bare hands.
罗伯特·格林伍德
Robert Greenwood.
杀害并吃掉了十多名女性
Killed and then ate a dozen women.
芭芭拉·基恩
Barbara Kean.
杀害了她父母
Killed her parents.
我们要分成四人小组行动
We're gonna work this in groups of four.
我会给你们分配今天的任务
I'll hand out assignments throughout the day.
阿尔瓦雷斯将协助我开展工作
Alvarez is my coordinating officer.
有问题吗
Any questions?
开始干活儿吧
Let's get to work.
昨天干得不错  各位
Fine job yesterday, gentlemen.
开场轰动全城
We opened big.
你们的名字已经街知巷闻了
The whole city knows your name now.
好极了  为自己鼓掌欢呼吧
So, bravo. Let's give ourselves a round of applause.
我们已经引起了哥谭的关注
Now that we have Gotham's attention,
疯子帮该隆重登场了
it's time for the Maniax to make a grand entrance.
昨天的不是吗
Wasn't that it?
昨天的只是序曲
That was the overture.
现在观众们都屏息期待
Now the audience is hushed, expectant.
帷幕升起
The curtain rises...
然后呢
Then what happens?
然后  我们出现在哥谭市民面前
Oh, then we confront Gothamites
带去他们最原始的恐惧
with their most primal fears.
夺走他们所有珍视及崇敬的东西
Take from them all they hold dear and sacred.
然后呢
And then what happens?
然后我们拯救他们
Why, then, we offer them salvation.
接着他们就是我们的了
And then they are ours.
开始忙起来吧
Let's get busy, man.
耐心点
Patience.
首先  你们要学会演戏
First, you gentlemen need to learn a little stagecraft.
演戏
Stagecraft?
你们就要上电视了
You're going to be on TV.
要展现出自己的风格与活力
You have to present yourselves with style and vigor.
道布金斯说  晚上好  女士们先生们
Dobkins, say "Good evening, ladies and gentlemen."
晚上好  女士们先生们
Good evening, ladies and gentlemen.
微笑着再说一次
Again, with a smile.
晚上好  女士们先生们
Good evening, ladies and gentlemen.
你来
You.
晚上好  女士们先生们
Good evening, ladies and gentlemen!
还不错
Not bad.
邪恶且有威严
Sinister and authoritative.
你就算了
Never mind.
杰罗姆
Jerome.
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
晚上好
good evening!
非常好
Very good.
稚嫩而有魅力
Boyishly charming.
笑声好极了
The laugh is fabulous.
用上吧
Use that.
轮到我了
Now me.
非常高兴你们俩能合得来
I am so glad that you two are getting along,
但我们还正忙着呢
but we're a little busy here,
所以你们能放过可怜的市长吗
so if you could leave the poor mayor alone...
我们无聊死了
We're bored.
是啊  为什么只有男生能玩
Yeah. Why do the boys get to have all the fun?
你们马上就有机会了
Your time is coming.
我跟你们说过了
I told you.
你们不是弄死他了吧
You haven't killed him, have you?
没  我想没有
No, I don't think so.
没有  还撑着呢
Nope. Hanging in there.
什么时候
When?
我什么时候有机会
When is my time coming?
很快
Soon.
非常快
Very soon.
你跟我说说詹姆斯·戈登吧
Why don't you tell me about James Gordon.
你想知道什么
What do you want to know?
真难以相信
It's hard to believe.
我父亲多年来经常偷偷溜下来
My father's been sneaking down here for years,
我却一点不知道
and I never even knew about it.
咱俩都是  不是吗
That makes two of us, doesn't it?
等下
Wait.
咱们先考虑一下
Let's just think about this.
你确定想要打开那玩意吗
Are you certain you want to turn that bloody thing on?
我当然确定
Of course I'm certain.
你真想清楚了吗  布鲁斯少爷
Have you thought it through, Master Bruce?
这电脑可能包含了我父亲所有
This computer could contain all my father's
关于韦恩集团的研究
research into Wayne Enterprises.
这么久以来  我一直在寻找确凿证据[冒烟的枪]
All this time, I've been looking for a smoking gun,
而它就在这里
and here it is.
没错  冒烟的枪
Exactly. A smoking gun.
但是  枪是给成年人用的  对不对
Now, guns are for grown-ups, aren't they?
那只是个比喻  阿尔弗雷德  不要较真
That's a metaphor, Alfred, not an argument.
好了
Here it is.
打开了
It's working!
你...你在干什么
What are you... What are you doing?!
阿尔弗雷德  停下  你在干什么
Alfred, stop! What are you doing?!
不要  你在干什么  阿尔弗雷德
No, what are you doing, Alfred?!
阿尔弗雷德  停下
Alfred, stop it!
都毁了
It's ruined!
都毁了  你这是犯什么病
It's ruined! What's wrong with you?!
你为什么要这么做  回答我
Why would you do that?! Answer me!
必须如此  布鲁斯少爷
It had to be done, Master Bruce!
这是揭露韦恩集团的关键
This was the key to exposing Wayne Enterprises.
我所有的努力
Everything that I've worked for,
我父亲的全部心血  现在都没了
everything my... everything my dad worked for is now gone!
都怪你
Because of you!
假如我知道这下面有什么
If I'd known what was down here,
我绝对不会帮你进来的
I would have never helped get you in.
你看看四周  看看  几升的血浆
I mean, look around you. Look, look. Liters of blood.
嵌着两颗子弹的防弹衣
A bulletproof vest with two slugs in it!
枪支  武器
Guns, weapons!
无论那台电脑里有什么
I mean, whatever's on that computer
大概就是你父亲丧命的原因
probably killed your father,
我绝对不会
and I'll be damned
让你遭受同样的命运  布鲁斯少爷
if I see you suffer the same fate, Master Bruce.
我是想保护你
I'm trying to protect you.
我是想让你平平安安的
I'm trying to keep you safe.
我要你离开
I want you to go.
-听着  我知道你...  -不
- Look, I know that you're... - No.
-很难过  你...  -阿尔弗雷德
- that you're upset, you... - Alfred.
我要你离开
I want you to go
再也不要回来了  明白吗
and never come back, do you understand me?
你被解雇了
You're fired.
好吧  布鲁斯少爷
Very well, Master Bruce.
如您所愿
As you wish.
真亮
Shiny.
还给我
Give that back.
我先看到的
I saw it first.
不  不是你
No, you didn't.
我说了还给我
I said give it back.
逼我啊  你个小屁孩
Make me, you little brat.
您的武士技艺非常出色  格林伍德先生
Your samurai skills are excellent Greenwood San,
但与我相比不值一提
but they are nothing compared to me.
受死吧
Prepare to die!
够了
That's enough! I said...
我想阻止他们来着
I tried to stop them.
伙计们  我们是一个团队
Boys, we're a team.
我们不内讧
We don't fight amongst ourselves.
没错  我们是一个团队  伙计们
Yeah, we're a team, boys.
而我是队长
And I'm the captain.
队长个屁
Captain of my foot.
我杀过一打女人
I've murdered a dozen women.
使整座城市陷入恐慌
Terrorized the city.
你做过什么
What have you done?
杀了你妈吗
Chop up your mommy?
人总得有个起点
Everybody has to start somewhere.
我有远见  有野心  有脑子
See, I have vision and ambition and brains.
你不过是个疯癫的食人魔
You're just a nutty old cannibal.
你再吃几个  这招就不新鲜了
How many people can you eat before that shtick gets old?
再吃一个你
I could eat one more.
看来咱们得来个终极较量了
I can see we're gonna have to resolve this one once and for all.
-这游戏会玩吧  -大爱
- You all know this game, right? - Oh, love it.
谁想当老大
Who wants to be the boss?
女士优先
Ladies first.
格林伍德
Hey, Greenwood,
什么才是优秀喜剧的诀窍
what's the secret to good comedy?
时机
Timing.
那什么是勇气呢
And what's courage?
压力面前保持优雅
Grace under pressure.
那么...
And...
谁是老大
...who's the boss?
我是老大
I'm the boss.
就是你  杰罗姆
I believe you are, Jerome.
你就是老大
I believe you are.
谢谢  老师
Arigato, sensei.
谢谢
Thank you.
四个疯子再加上芭芭拉
Four lunatics and Barbara?
兄弟  你真够霉的
Brother, you got no luck.
都说了当平民百姓舒服多了  是不是
I told you civilian life was better, didn't I?
你的确说过
Yeah, you did.
其实这正是我来的目的
Actually, that's kind of why I'm here.
-是吗  -是的
- Yeah? - Yeah.
你来干吗
What are you doing here?
吉姆  你还记得斯科蒂吧  我女朋友
Jim, you remember Scotty, my girlfriend.
是未婚妻
Fiancée.
是  我未婚妻
Right, my fiancée.
记得  斯科蒂  很高兴见到你
Yeah, Scotty, good to see you.
别紧张  亲爱的  我俩聊天而已
Relax, honey bun. We're just talking.
那就见鬼了
Oh, like hell you are.
他是想请你回警局
He's gonna ask you to come back to work.
他什么都没说
He didn't ask me anything.
-我俩闲聊而已  -是吗
- We're just having a chat. - Oh, is that right?
你是为这来找他吗  警探
Is that why you're here, Detective?
闲聊
Just to have a chat?
不  不是  她说得没错
No, no. She's right.
哈维  我需要你的帮助  这案子不好对付
Harvey, I need your help. The case is a bear.
我们很缺人手  我在想也许你...
We're short-handed, and, uh, I was thinking maybe you could...
他有自己的生活
He has a life.
答案是不  他不会回去的
The answer is no. He is not coming back.
亲爱的  我是要拒绝他的
Hon. I'm telling him no.
但就像她说的
But it's like she said,
我现在有生活了
I have a life.
我理解
I get it.
我为你高兴
I'm happy for you.
就是个想法
Just a thought.
-祝我好运吧  -好运
- Wish me luck. - Good luck.
吉姆  还有件事  你哈维叔叔
Jim, one last thing. One last thought
最后给你一句忠告
from your Uncle Harvey.
这个疯子帮杀了一群船坞的人  对吧
These Maniax killed a bunch of people from the shipyard, right?
耶伦船坞  没错
Yellen Shipyard, yeah.
为什么是那里
Why there?
他们大可以去任何地方  杀任何人
They could've gone anywhere, killed anyone.
但这些疯子却偏偏选了这个船坞  我
But these lunatics specifically chose that shipyard. I...
想知道为什么
wonder why.
见到你真好
Good to see you.
斯科蒂
Scotty.
好  稍后给您回电
Yeah. Call you back.
局长
Commissioner!
拜托给我个好消息吧
Tell me something good. Please.
-哈维不回来了  -这可不是好消息
- Harvey isn't coming back. - That's not good.
但他提出了一条线索  我还真查到东西了
But he did suggest a lead that panned out nicely.
原来疯子帮昨天从船坞
Turns out, the Maniax stole a refueling truck
偷了一辆加油车
from the shipyard yesterday.
为什么没有报失
Why wasn't it reported?
因为在役车辆有一百多
It was one of over a hundred service vehicles.
点一遍车队花了点时间
Took a while to track down the entire fleet.
但点完后  我们发现有一辆失踪了
But when we did, we found that one was missing.
上满装满了汽油
Fully loaded with gasoline.
知道车牌号了吗
You get a license plate?
还知道车的外形特征
And a description of the vehicle.
发了全境通告
Put out an APB.
-真高兴你回来了  吉姆  -我也是
- God, I'm so glad you're back, Jim. - Me, too.
真希望我也能对布洛克说这句话
Wish I could say the same for Bullock.
真不敢相信他真不回来了
I-I can't believe he's really gone.
他是个警察
He's a cop.
天生就是警察的料
He was born to be a cop.
不再是了  他现在很幸福
Not anymore. He's a happy man.
我实在不忍心为难他
I didn't have it in me to push him.
你考虑过吗
You ever think about that?
我是说离开
Walking away, I mean.
没有  你呢
No. You?
想过  想过很久
I did, for a long time.
现在不了吗
But not anymore?
我一直冷眼旁观那些腐败  懒惰的人
I've sat back and watched all the corrupt, lazy men
靠钱干上这个职位  却毫无作为
buy their way into this job and waste it.
我不会  吉姆
Not me, Jim.
我绝不会
Not me.
-这是新的一天  -太对了
- A new day. - You're damn right.
我只想说  能服务您和您的家人
I'd just like to say it's been an honor
是我莫大的荣幸  先生
and a privilege to serve you and your family, sir.
谢谢
Thank you.
如果需要推荐信  我很乐意给你写
If you need any references, I'll be happy to provide them.
就带这些吗
Is that all you're taking with you?
这是我的一切了  先生
It's all I have, sir.
好了  那...
Right. Well, um...
天啊  我得赶紧走了
Oh, dear, yes. I best be off.
我还要赶火车呢
I've got a train to catch.
再见  先生
Good-bye, sir.
再见  阿尔弗雷德
Good-bye, Alfred.
什么事  先生
Beg your pardon, sir?
我说  再见
I said good-bye.
是啊
Yes.
再见了  先生
Good-bye, sir.
我用我的小眼睛搜索着
I spy with my little eye
寻找那一抹...
something that is...
黄色
...yellow.
得分  哥谭  得分得分再得分
Score, Gotham, score! We want more!
打得他们落花又流水
Hit 'em where it hurts and knock 'em to the floor!
冲啊  哥谭
Yay, Gotham!
好啊  柯林格小姐
Hello, Ms. Kringle.
你好  尼格玛先生
Hello, Mr. Nygma.
今天过得好吗
How's your day going?
还行
Fine.
问你个问题
Um, question for you.
什么事
Y-Yes?
你知道家蝇的嗡嗡声是F调的吗
Did you know that houseflies hum in the key of F?
不知道
No.
我不知道
No, I-I did not know that.
那好吧
Okay, then.
-那再见了  -再见
- Well, uh... bye. - Bye.
该死
Damn it!
我们不是说好要约她出去的嘛
We agreed you were going to ask her out.
我们没说好要约她
No, we didn't agree to ask her.
只是说好考虑约她
We agreed to think about asking her.
但没用的
But there's no point.
她又不喜欢你
She doesn't like you.
或许她会喜欢我
Maybe she'll like me.
这你想过吗
You ever consider that?
或许她会喜欢我
Maybe she'll like me.
我自信
I got confidence.
女孩喜欢那个
Ladies love that.
不  她不会喜欢你的
No, she won't like you.
她不会的  走开
She won't. Go away.
走开吧
Please, just go away!
看到被盗油车了  在伊弗利公园
We got a sighting of the stolen truck. Yeavely Park.
我想告诉你们
I want you all to know
这对我们来说是个艰难的抉择
this was a very difficult decision for us.
要么是你们  要么就是一群老头老太太
It was between you and a senior citizen bingo party.
最后  我们还是决定要嫩的
In the end, we decided to skew a little younger.
青春赢了
Youth won the day.
抱歉
Sorry.
喊个O
Give me an "O"!
我说  喊个O
I said give me a "O."
O
"O."
喊个N
Give me an "N."
-N  -再喊个O
- "N." - Give me another "O"!
-O  -拼成了什么
- "O." - What does that spell?
不要啊
"Oh, no!"
动手  动手  动手吧
Do it! Do it! Do it!
准备好了吗  好嘞
Ready? Okay!
这下尴尬了
This is so embarrassing.
有人有火吗
Anyone got a light?
我有  我有
I do. I got...
站稳了  伙计们
Stand your ground, boys.
他们不敢打大巴
They can't shoot at a bus.
别开火  别开火
Hold your fire! Hold your fire!
亚伦  格林伍德  去启动油车
Aaron, Greenwood, get the truck started.
我们要把这车炸飞
We're gonna blow this barbecue.
点了他们
Light 'em up!
大家没事吧
Everybody okay?
谁帮你越狱的  道布金斯
Who broke you out, Dobkins?
你迟早得说  赶紧告诉我
Gonna have to talk sooner or later; tell me now.
我也是受害者  长官  我是被逼的
I'm a victim here, sir. I was coerced.
被绑  被逼
Abducted and coerced.
-谁  -如果要我说
- By who? - If I tell you that,
你得保证  我不会...
I got to get some kind of guaran...
我知道你是想保护我
I understand you were just trying to protect me.
但是不论怎样
But there's nothing...
不管你做什么  都不能阻止我
nothing that you can do to stop me
继承父亲的遗志
from carrying out my father's work.
我现在知道了
I know that now.
我不希望你走  阿尔弗雷德
I don't want you to go, Alfred.
但你要么跟我站在一边  要么就是与我对立
But you're either with me or you're against me.
你如果与我对立  我将别无选择
And if you're against me, I don't have a choice.
我当然跟你一边  布鲁斯少爷  我一向如此
I'm with you, Master Bruce. I've always been with you.
但你在做的事等同于自杀
But what you're doing is tantamount to suicide.
这是大人干的事
This is big boy stuff.
你还太小  没准备好
You're too young; you're not ready.
那就帮我准备好
Then make me ready.
你经历了危险的人生  却还活了下来
You-You've lived a dangerous life, and you survived.
教我吧
So teach me.
教我如何生存下来
Teach me how to do the same.
我会不惜一切  天天训练
I'll do whatever it takes. I'll train every day.
这话你之前就说过
Yeah, well, you said that before, didn't you?
那是之前
That was before.
现在我知道了真相
Now I know the truth.
我知道我该做什么
And I know what I have to do.
如果你想  我愿意回学校
I'll even go back to school if you want.
是嘛
School, even?
如果我答应帮你  帮你做准备
If I agree to help you, to make you ready,
你要完全听我的  令行禁止
you must do exactly as I say and when I say it
绝无例外  懂了吗
with no exceptions, is that understood?
懂了
Understood.
但作为交换  你得修好电脑
But, in return, you must fix that computer.
修电脑
Fix it?
这我怎么做到啊
How on earth am I gonna do that?
我不管
That's not my problem.
又不是我打坏的
I'm not the one who broke it.
大口径  高速度
High caliber, high velocity.
从伤口大小来看
Judging by the size of the wounds,
绝对是隔着一定距离开的枪
it was definitely shot from some distance.
此人是个好枪手
Someone knew how to shoot.
究竟是谁啊
Who, damn it?
为什么绑架拉拉队  有什么动机
And why cheerleaders? Where's the motive?
他们都不索要赎金
They didn't even ask for a ransom.
他们要的是宣传
They want headlines.
要大众惶恐
They want mass panic.
-他们如愿了  -是啊
- Well, they got it. - Yeah.
看看能不能查到子弹来头
Let's see if we can't I.D. that bullet.
说不准啊
Never know your luck.
-还撑着呢  -撑着呢
- Holding up? - Holding up.
爱你
Love you.
我也是
Likewise.
来杯金汤力  加冰和柠檬片
Gin and tonic, please, uh, governor. Ice and a slice.
这里不错
Nice place.
是啊
It is.
以前来过
Been here before, then, have you?
常客
It's my regular spot.
对了  你是本地人
Oh, right, you're a local.
不错
Nice.
我认识你吧
Don't I know you?
是吗
Do you?
是啊
Yeah.
你是那个福克斯先生
You're that Mr. Fox,
韦恩集团的科技人员  是吧
that scientific chap from Wayne Enterprises, ain't you?
是的
That is me.
阿尔弗雷德·潘尼沃斯
Alfred Pennyworth.
布鲁斯少爷的监护人
Young Master Bruce Wayne's guardian.
是啊
Ah, yes.
挺有意思啊
It's a funny old game though, isn't it?
我这么巧碰到了你
Coincidence, I mean, me bumping into you like this. I mean...
我刚刚正想你呢
I was just thinking about you.
好吧  潘尼沃斯先生  我上你的钩
Okay, Mr. Pennyworth, I'll bite.
你想我什么呢
What were you thinking about me?
喊我阿尔弗雷德就行
Oh, "Alfred," please.
喊我卢修斯就好
Please, "Lucius."
卢修斯  卢修斯
Lucius. Lucius.
知道吗
You know...
我以前认识个叫昂斯洛的家伙
I once knew this geezer called Onslow
伦敦东区恶犬岛的
in the Isle of Dogs in the East End of London.
就是个小流氓
Lairy little scallywag, he was.
油头滑脑  我一直不信任他
He was, uh, too smart by half; never trusted him.
有一天  卢修斯  他跑来跟我套近乎
Anyway, one day, Lucius, he comes bowling up to me,
叫我帮他忙  感觉很可疑
and he asks me to do him this right iffy favor.
具体是什么不要紧
Oh, it doesn't matter what it was.
重点是  我虽然觉得不该帮
The point being, against my better judgment,
但还是答应了
I agreed to do it.
但是  卢修斯  我直截了当地说了
But, Lucius, I told him, I told him straight, I said,
你敢坑我  昂斯洛
"You let me down, Onslow,
看我把你做成腌鱼
I'll tuck you up, sunshine, like a kipper."
他立刻发了毒誓
He swears blind,
以他母亲的坟墓发誓他绝不会坑我
swears on his mother's grave he'd never do such a thing,
但他当然还是坑了
but of course he did.
就是忍不住
Couldn't help himself; he let me down.
我也说到做到了
So I tucked him up.
把他变成了腌鱼
Like a kipper.
腌鱼是什么
What is a kipper?
是一种熏鱼
It's a type of smoked fish.
配鸡蛋烤吐司当早餐很不错
Very nice with eggs and brown toast for breakfast.
但昂斯洛让我明白
But what I learned from Onslow is this.
这世上有两种人
There are two types of people on this planet, you see.
你可以信任的
Them you can trust...
你不能信任的
and them you can't.
我同意
I cannot disagree.
你是哪种
Which kind are you?
两种人对这个问题
Both kinds of people would give you
不是都会给出一样的答案吗
the same answer, wouldn't they?
是啊
Exactly.
说得太对了
Exactly right.
问题就在这里  卢修斯
There lieth the problem, Lucius.
我需要跟你说些秘密
You see, I need to confide in you.
但我需要知道你值得信任
But I need to know that you're trustworthy.
或许我该拒不听你吐露秘密
Perhaps I should decline your confidence.
那腌鱼听上去不太舒服
I don't like the sound of these kippers.
可惜  已经来不及了
Yeah, well, it's a bit late for that, unfortunately.
毕竟  是你  卢修斯  制造了这堆麻烦
I mean, it's you, after all, Lucius, that created this mess
是你告诉布鲁斯少爷  他死去的老爸
when you told young Master Bruce that his dear old dead dad...
是个斯多葛学派的人
was a stoic.
是啊
"Ah," exactly.
现在有个问题
You see, there's a problem.
我没有别人可以求助
I got no one else to turn to.
我只能找你
I have to confide in you.
我明白了
I see.
真的吗
Do you?
我说清楚
Let me just be crystal clear about this.
如果我发现
If it turns out...
我其实不能信任你
that I can't trust you,
我以我母亲的坟墓发誓
I swear on my mother's grave,
你  老伙计
you, my old sausage...
就死定了
...are a dead man.
我一心只为布鲁斯·韦恩好
I have only the best intentions for Bruce Wayne.
再来杯金汤力
Well, another gin and tonic please, uh, governor.
再给这位年轻人来一杯他喝的
And whatever this young man is drinking, one for yourself.
你擅长修电脑吗
How are you at fixing computers?
阿尔瓦雷斯
Hey, Alvarez!
让弹道分析加急做这个
Let ballistics know we got a red ball for them, will you?
好的
On it.
戈登
Gordon.
吉姆  我是芭芭拉
Hello, Jim. It's Barbara.
芭芭拉
Hi, Barbara.
你好吗
How are you?
我吗  我好极了
Oh, me? I'm fabulous.
你呢
How are you?
我挺好  最近干吗呢
I'm good. What's new?
酷哥先生啊
Mr. Cool Guy, huh?
你一定很生我气吧
You must be so mad at me.
听我说
Listen to me.
如果你自首  我能帮你
If you turn yourself in, I can help you.
怎么帮  吉姆
How, Jim?
送我回阿卡姆吗
By taking me back to Arkham?
还是算了
I don't think so.
你有病
You're sick.
当然了
Of course.
事事都是我的错
Everything's always my fault.
总是如此
So typical.
听我说
Listen to me.
我了解你  芭芭拉
I know you, Barbara.
我了解你
I know you.
你是个善良的女人
You're a good, kind woman.
这不是你
This isn't you.
你总能逗我笑
You could always make me laugh.
我看上去如何
How do I look?
我要马上找艾森局长
I need to talk to Commissioner Essen right away.
是急事
It's an emergency.
往前走  她在楼上
Yeah, go ahead. She's right upstairs.
局长
Yo, Commish.
嗯
Yeah?
听说你在找我们
Heard you were looking for us.
搞什么
What the hell?
放下枪
Put it down.
芭芭拉
Barbara!
别动
Don't move.
你看错我了  吉姆
You're wrong about me, Jim.
我想告诉你的  你就是不听
I tried telling you, but you never listen.
我现在听了
I'm listening now.
是啊  现在听了
Yeah, sure you are. Now.
得了
Come on.
我们谈谈吧
Let's go talk this through, huh?
已经太迟了
Oh, it's too late for that.
亚伦
Aaron.
够了
That's enough.
我没病  我是自由了
I'm not sick. I'm free.
你就是不懂
You don't get that.
我可以跟你解释
I could explain it,
但你还是赶紧回单位吧
but you should probably get back to work.
谁知道你不在时出了什么乱子呢
Who knows what went wrong while you were gone?
局长大人第一周真不顺利啊
Hell of a first week you're having, Commissioner.
真希望我能说
I wish I could tell you that
今后情况会有所好转
things were gonna get better for you.
但不会的
They're not.
来  拿上来
Here, bring that up here.
找个更好的角度拍下整间屋子
Get a better angle of the room.
你为什么要这么做
Why are you doing this?
统治世界
To rule the world.
不过能杀杀警察  出出风头我们就满足了
But we'll settle for some dead cops and some good P.R.
开玩笑的
Kidding.
嗯  随便吧  我懂了
Yeah. Whatever. I get it.
你就是个疯子
You're just crazy.
疯子
"Crazy"?
看看我
Look at me.
你可以看得出我没疯
You can see I'm not crazy.
小子  很快
Very soon, little man,
你就会没命
you will be dead.
世界离了你会照样转
And the world will go on without you.
你会什么都不是
You'll be nothing.
甚至不会有人记住你的姓名
No one will even remember your name.
不
No.
这你就错了  老太婆
That is where you're wrong, old lady.
我们会在这城市留下印记
We will leave a mark on this city.
我们会像病毒一样在其中蔓延
We will spread across it like a virus.
知道为什么吗
Do you know why?
因为笑声是最具感染性的了
There's nothing more contagious than laughter.
那是我的台词
My line.
笑声是最具感染性的了
There's nothing more contagious than laughter.
格外得舒爽啊
That was strangely pleasant.
再来一次
Do it again.
这会给你留下印记
That's gonna leave a mark.
被你整到了
You got me.
该我了
My turn.
小莱
Lee?
吉姆
Jim!
你受伤了吗
You hurt?
没有  我当时待在办公室
No. I... I-I was in my office,
听到外面有枪声就躲了起来
and I heard gunfire and I hid.
你去哪了
Where were you?
芭芭拉来过  把我引了出去
Barbara was here. She lured me away.
艾森
Essen!
撑住  警监  撑住
Hang on, Cap, hang on.
老大  老大  撑住了
Boss, boss, stay with me.
呼吸
Breathe.
是新的一天
It's a new day...
吉姆
Jim.
这是
This is...
真坏了
indeed broken.
我有好多问题想问你
I have a lot of questions for you.
我猜也是
I imagine so.
我父亲把一切都告诉你了吗
Did my father tell you everything?
当然没有
Heavens no.
你父亲很注重隐私
Your father, he was a very private man.
没办法
He had to be.
我不过是给予了技术支持
I simply helped with technical resources,
比如这台电脑
like this computer.
你知道上面有什么吗
Do you know what's on it?
不  老实说  我不想知道
No. I didn't want to know, to be honest.
你能修好它吗
But you can fix it?
应该可以
I should think so.
但得耗点时间了
But it is going to take some time.
谢谢你帮忙
Well, um, thank you for your help.
我敬爱你父亲
I loved your father.
我后悔从未跟他说过这话
I regret that I never told him so.
也后悔没有给他更多帮助
I regret that I didn't help him more.
把烙铁递给我好吗
Hand me the soldering iron, will you?
嗯
Yeah.
布鲁斯少爷
Master Bruce?
怎么了  阿尔弗雷德
What is it, Alfred?
你怎么样  尼格玛先生
How you doing, Mr. Nygma?
我给你拿了阿司匹林
I got you an aspirin.
谢谢
Thank you.
戈登警探
Detective Gordon!
布鲁斯
Bruce.
我听到了新闻
I heard the news. I...
我担心你出事了
I was worried something happened to you.
现在我放心了
I'm very relieved.
我也是
Me, too.
我们上次见时  我对你太过分了
Th-The last time that we met, I was... I was very hard on you.
我想道歉
I wanted to apologize.
你一直待我很好
You've been a really good friend.
她是个好女人
She was a good woman.
好警察
Good cop.
见到你我很高兴  但你不用这样的
It's good to see you, but you don't have to do this.
别说了
Let's not talk about it.
我们是什么改不了  是吧
We are who we are, right?
没必要抗拒
No use fighting it.
斯科蒂怎么说
What does Scotty say?
她会理解的
She'll understand.
也或许不会
Or she won't.
伙计们
Guys.
你们得看看这个
You need to see this.
我正在哥谭市警局屠杀现场向您做报道
I'm reporting live from the scene of the GCPD massacre.
我们刚刚拿到了袭击的录像带
We have just obtained video footage of the attack
是由一位袭击者录制的
recorded by one of the assailants.
提醒观众们
I want to warn those of you watching,
以下录像
what you're about to see
十分血腥
is very graphic.
哥谭市好啊
Hello, Gotham City!
我们是疯子帮
We're the Maniax.
我是杰罗姆  我们小帮派的头头
And I'm Jerome, the shot caller of our little gang.
我们是来散播智慧和希望的讯息的
We're here to spread the message of wisdom and hope.
有些人真没礼貌
Some people have no manners.
你们都是囚徒
You're all prisoners.
你们所谓的正常
What you call sanity,
只是你脑中的牢笼  让你看不清
it's just a prison in your minds that stops you from seeing
你不过是一台巨大荒谬的机器中的
that you're just little tiny cogs
一块小齿轮
in a giant absurd machine.
醒醒吧
Wake up!
为什么要做个齿轮
Why be a cog?
像我们一样  自由吧
Be free like us.
记得微笑
Just remember, smile.
该走了
Time to go.
不过别担心
But don't worry.
我们很快就会回来
We'll be back very soon.
准备好了  伙计们
Hang on to your hats, folks.
这还不算什么呢
'Cause you ain't seen nothing yet!